<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Stuifbergen</title>
    <description>This is a means to share some knowledge and experience I&#39;ve picked up over the years and a way to share some of the craziness going on in my head.</description>
    <link>http://johnstuifbergen.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://johnstuifbergen.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 21:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 21:35:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>35 Lessons. 35 Years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I turned 35 this year. While attending Big Omaha, I heard one of the speakers tell a story how, when he turned 35, he wrote down a list of things he’d learned in life. I thought, “I should do that!”. Then I thought, “what if I can’t come up with 35 things…”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posts that follow are a somewhat random ordered list of experiences, quotes, and conversations that I feel have been incredible life lessons that have helped me get to the here and now, and moderately. I’ve done my best to attribute each lesson to a person or circumstance. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 21:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnstuifbergen.com/blog/35-lessons</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnstuifbergen.com/blog/35-lessons</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>35-things</category>
        
        
        <category>35-things</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Backup iPhone Photos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing families, i.e. babies, obviously require TONS of photos. Falling close behind, of course, are selfies, things we’re about to eat, and place I am &amp;amp; you’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I field a fair amount of phone calls from friends and family members about technological issues. One question that I’ve seem to get over &amp;amp; over:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’ve run out of space on my iPhone, how do I back-up my photos?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this seems pretty simple: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug iPhone into computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save photos from said iPhone to hard drive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Erase photos from iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unplug&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take more photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Yes, but then I lose 24/7 access to them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ok-you-can-have-your-cake-and-eat-it-too&quot;&gt;Ok, you can have your cake and eat it too!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s state the problem, just so we’re all on the same page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily back-up photos on an iPhone, free up storage, but still have access to all your photos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;icloud&quot;&gt;iCloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reaction is to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://iCloud.com&quot;&gt;iCloud&lt;/a&gt;. While that’s certainly is a great way to BACK-UP your photos. Look around for a solution and you’ll quickly become confused w/ the different scenarios that will and won’t work. Long story short, you’ll end up losing photos sooner or later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr, if you don’t know, is a cloud service for photos and video. Their free account is quite awesome. One terabyte of storage (that’s 62 iPhones). The photos are yours and you can adjust the privacy and sharing levels to limit how they appear in searches and who can see them. &lt;em&gt;I have my privacy set to the max - the only people that can see my photos are my family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-iphone-flickr-app&quot;&gt;The iPhone Flickr App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might have guessed, Flickr has an iPhone app - which has a preference setting to automatically send the photos from your camera roll to your Flickr account (that is, as long as you have the Flickr app running in the background). You can also select the photos from inside iPhone’s camera app and send them to Flickr manually. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both solutions work quite well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is to go with Flickr, &lt;strong&gt;it’s easy, free, &amp;amp; reliable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 21:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnstuifbergen.com/blog/iphone-photos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnstuifbergen.com/blog/iphone-photos</guid>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
